<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>12 хиляди години минаха</title>
    <description>Съвършено друг поглед за произхода на климатичните промени!</description>
    <link>https://twelvepassed.life/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://twelvepassed.life/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 12:08:16 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 12:08:16 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ПЪРВОПРИЧИНАТА ЗА НЕПРЕДВИДИМИТЕ ПРОМЕНИ ВЪВ ВРЕМЕТО</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Климатът става хаотичен и е все по-невъзможно да се предвиди поведението му.
Сезоните си сменят местата. Необичайни метеорологични аномалии се случват навсякъде. И ако се появят в региона, в който живеете, тогава знайте че първопричината за всички промени в климата е издигането на магма към земната кора по целия свят. Нагряването на долните слоеве на атмосферата, океаните и ледниците свидетелства за издигането на магмата и образуването на нови магмени потоци, които разяждат мантията и се приближават до кората.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Световни институти за изследване на атмосферата са установили, че един от регионите, където повишаването на температурата е 2-3 пъти по-бързо от средното за света, е Сибир. Установено било, че през 1998 г. ядрото на планетата се е изместило в тази посока. Поради това магмата под Сибир се издига най-бързо към повърхността. И сега под него има огромна магмена камера, която си проправя път през кората.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Нагряването на недрата води до аномално размразяване на вечната замръзналост и газови експлозии под леда. В арктическата част на Сибир са се появили зимни пожари под снега. В зоните над разломите ледената вода в кладенците на хората става гореща, увеличава се броят и силата на земетресенията.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Друг признак за аномално нагряване на почвата е топенето на ледниците отдолу нагоре. Американският геолог и изследовател Джеймс Камис отбелязва, че в Антарктида ледниците Туейтс и Пайн Айлънд се топят отдолу поради увеличения топлинен поток от недрата. В Западна Антарктика, която е вулканична област, топлинни аномалии се появиха под лед с дебелина 2 километра, точно на местата на вулканите. Това е така, защото от 1995 г. се е активирала огромна магмена камера дълбоко под тънката кора на Антарктида в района на Земята Мери Бърд.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Подобна ситуация се наблюдава и в Гренландия под централната част на острова. От 1995 г. се е активирала магмена камера, която увеличава скоростта на топене на леда независимо от сезона.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Друг много опасен признак за издигането на магмата е нагряването на океанското дъно отдолу.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Магмата, която е започнала да се издига от дълбините в огромни мащаби, се вгражда в океанската кора, подобно на червей, който прояжда кората на дърво. Това кара водата на дъното да се нагрява и да се издига на повърхността. Като цяло през последните 30 години това нагряване е с 450% по-голямо и по-бързо в сравнение с предишния период. В резултат както средните слоеве на океана, така и дълбоките слоеве от 4 km и по-надолу се затоплят много по-бързо, отколкото би трябвало.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;А през лятото на 2023 г. всички възможни рекорди за нагряване на океана бяха счупени. Това затопляне на океана увеличава количеството пара в атмосферата, а това води до&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;увеличаване на броя на ураганите и бурите,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;увеличаване на количеството на валежите под формата на аномални дъждове, снеговалежи и едра градушка.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;По подобен начин на континентите поради издигането на магмата подземните води започват да се изпаряват аномално, което води до увеличаване на рекордните валежи и наводнения. Имайки предвид глобалния характер на протичащите процеси и катастрофалния характер на последствията от тях за всеки от нас, сега е изключително важно да се способства за създаването на международен единен научен център за изследване на климатичните промени и начините за тяхното балансиране. Днес трябва да направим темата за изучаване на климата във въпрос по целия свят и съвместно да насочим всичките си човешки ресурси към неговото разрешаване. Защото цената му е оцеляването на човечеството.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🧑‍💻 Споделяйте информацията.
Абонирайте се за &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/klimat_realnost&quot;&gt;телеграм канала&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://twelvepassed.life/magma-under-syberia/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twelvepassed.life/magma-under-syberia/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Climate</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Земетресение в сложна обстановка</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Измина една година, откакто в Южна Турция се случиха два големи разлома, които предизвикаха силно усетени и опустошителни земетресения.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Земетресението в Пазарджик с магнитуд 7,8 беше последвано девет часа по-късно от земетресението в Елбистан с магнитуд 7,5, сега общо известно като земетресенията в Кахраманмараш, на името на един от тежко пострадалите градове. Светът изведнъж беше залят от изображения и видеоклипове на разрушенията. Броят на жертвите в крайна сметка нарасна до близо 60 000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Многобройните вторични трусове продължават по протежение и на двете сложни зони на разломите, които са се образували. Последният забележим трус се случи преди по-малко от две седмици: трус с магнитуд 5,2 близо до Малатия, който предизвика силно разтърсване близо до епицентъра си и беше усетен в целия регион.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Досега са регистрирани повече от 18 000 труса, въпреки че повечето са били твърде малки, за да бъдат усетени.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Земетресенията в Кахраманмараш предизвикаха широк спектър от повърхностни ефекти, включително повърхностни разломи, свлачища, скални падания, втечняване, хидроложки промени, щети на сгради и разрушаване на критично важна инфраструктура.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://twelvepassed.life/zem-turkish/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twelvepassed.life/zem-turkish/</guid>
        
        <category>Turkish</category>
        
        
        <category>Climate</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>КРЕМЪК И ОГНИВО</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Някои хора не разбират защо се говори за климата толкова често, някои дори се дразнят. А много хора смятат, че няма да могат да спрат развиващите се събития с климата, защото климатът не зависи от тях.
Тази притча ще помогне да се разсеят тези недоразбирания:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Кремъкът си лежал самотен сред скалите и смятал, че от него няма никаква полза и нищо в света не зависи от него.
Един човек го намерил и взел със себе си.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Получавайки един ден силен удар от огнивото, кремъкът възмутено попитал насилника:
– Защо се нахвърляш така върху мен? Аз теб не те познавам. Явно ме бъркаш с някого. Моля, остави крайщата ми на мира.
– Не се ядосвай напразно, съседе – с усмивка казал кремъкът в отговор. – Ако проявиш малко търпение, скоро ще видиш какво чудо ще създадем.
При тези думи кремъкът се успокоил и започнал търпеливо да понася ударите на когнивото. Търпението на кремъка било заслужено възнаградено.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Накрая, от него бил изсечен огън, способен да върши истински чудеса.
Благодарение на огъня хората успели да приготвят храна, да направят керамични изделия, а в ковачницата да изковат много необходими удивителни инструменти.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ударите на съдбата закаляват духа ни и ни дават възможност да видим това, което по-рано не сме можели да забележим.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Понякога търпението и смелите действия, при които преодоляваме трудностите, стартират поредица от невероятни събития.
Това се случва и в личен план, и в световен мащаб.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Сега нашият свят, заедно с нашата Планета, навлиза в цикъл от 12 000 години, при който стремително нараства климатичната криза. Климатът носи маса разрушения и отнема животи. В такива условия човек не може да оцелее сам.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;За решението на глобалния проблем, трябва да се обединят всички. Подобно на кремъка и огнивото, хората заедно, взаимодействайки се, ще могат да постигнат много. За общото оцеляване сега е важно да се създаде международен единен научен център за решение на климатичния проблем.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Не се ядосвайте, приятели, ако сега много хора като огниво се опитват да достигнат до вас и да изсекат искрата на разбирането.
Та нали без вашето участие, няма да се получи навреме да се предупреди света за заплахата и да се създаде масова заявка за оцеляване.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Всеки човек е важен и може да допринесе за това — да подкрепи общочовешката вълна, да говори за необходимостта от обединяване на науката, създаване на обществена заявка и да споделя информацията.
Заедно ще можем да достигнем до тези, от които зависи вземането на решения, та нали сега също и техния живот е в опасност.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Нашето общо дело, сплотеност и взаимопомощ могат да доведат не само до спасяването на планетата, но и до положителни промени в обществото, както и до много открития в науката..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🧑‍💻 Споделяйте информацията.
Абонирайте се за &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/klimat_realnost&quot;&gt;телеграм канала&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://twelvepassed.life/kramak-ognivo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twelvepassed.life/kramak-ognivo/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Climate</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>London is that kind of place you must visit in this lifetime</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Queen’s Guard and Queen’s Life Guard (called King’s Guard and King’s Life Guard when the reigning monarch is male) are the names given to contingents of infantry and cavalry soldiers charged with guarding the official royal residences in the United Kingdom. The British Army has regiments of both Horse Guards and Foot Guards predating the English Restoration (1660), and since the reign of King Charles II these regiments have been responsible for guarding the Sovereign’s palaces. The Guards are fully operational soldiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Queen’s Guard and Queen’s Life Guard are mounted at the royal residences that come under the operating area of the British Army’s London District, which is responsible for the administration of the Household Division. This covers Buckingham Palace, St James’s Palace and the Tower of London, as well as Windsor Castle. The Queen’s Guard is also mounted at the sovereign’s other official residence, the Palace of Holyroodhouse, but not as often as in London. In Edinburgh, the guard is the responsibility of the resident infantry battalion at Redford Barracks. It is not mounted at the Queen’s private residences at Sandringham or Balmoral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Queen’s Guard is the name given to the contingent of infantry responsible for guarding Buckingham Palace and St James’s Palace (including Clarence House) in London. The guard is made up of a company of soldiers from a single regiment, which is split in two, providing a detachment for Buckingham Palace and a detachment for St James’s Palace. Because the Sovereign’s official residence is still St James’s, the guard commander (called the captain of the guard) is based there, as are the regiment’s colours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Sovereign is in residence, the Queen’s Guard numbers three officers and forty other ranks, with four sentries each posted at Buckingham Palace (on the forecourt) and St James’s Palace (two in Friary Court, two at the entrance to Clarence House).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reduces to three officers and 31 ORs, with two sentries each, when the Sovereign is not in residence. The Queen’s Guard is not purely ceremonial in nature. They provide sentries during the day and night, and during the later hours, they patrol the grounds of the Palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until 1959, the sentries at Buckingham Palace were stationed outside the fence. This stopped following an incident involving a female tourist and a Coldstream Guardsman – due to the continued pestering by tourists and sightseers, the guardsman kicked the tourist on the ankle as he marched. The tourist made a complaint to the police and the sentry was confined to barracks for ten days. Not long after, the sentries were moved inside the fence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://twelvepassed.life/london/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twelvepassed.life/london/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Memoirs supports external images as featured</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Adding images is a very annoying task, I know that, but “Memoirs” theme has external featured images integrated so your publishing task becomes easier now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking. To think incisively and to think for one’s self is very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are prone to let our mental life become invaded by legions of half truths, prejudices, and propaganda. At this point, I often wonder whether or not education is fulfilling its purpose. A great majority of the so-called educated people do not think logically and scientifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the press, the classroom, the platform, and the pulpit in many instances do not give us objective and unbiased truths. To save man from the morass of propaganda, in my opinion, is one of the chief aims of education. Education must enable one to sift and weigh evidence, to discern the true from the false, the real from the unreal, and the facts from the fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The function of education, therefore, is to teach one to think intensively and to think critically. But education which stops with efficiency may prove the greatest menace to society. The most dangerous criminal may be the man gifted with reason, but with no morals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The late Eugene Talmadge, in my opinion, possessed one of the better minds of Georgia, or even America. Moreover, he wore the Phi Beta Kappa key. By all measuring rods, Mr. Talmadge could think critically and intensively; yet he contends that I am an inferior being. Are those the types of men we call educated?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must remember that intelligence is not enough. Intelligence plus character–that is the goal of true education. The complete education gives one not only power of concentration, but worthy objectives upon which to concentrate. The broad education will, therefore, transmit to one not only the accumulated knowledge of the race but also the accumulated experience of social living.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://twelvepassed.life/external-featured-image/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twelvepassed.life/external-featured-image/</guid>
        
        <category>France</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spoliers Inside - a film review needs hidden spoilers like this post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Director Roland Suso Richter’s enigmatic psychological thriller (direct to video/DVD) was based upon screenwriter Michael Cooney’s own play “Point of Death” - a title that gave away the film’s entire plot twist premise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As in many similar films, such as Jacob’s Ladder (1990), Soul Survivors (2001), and The Butterfly Effect (2004), events and people were thoroughly distorted and confused because the protagonist was at the point of death. The tagline was misleading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“When You Don’t Have a Memory, How Can You Remember Who to Trust?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mind-warping film opened with a hospital patient Simon Cable (Ryan Phillippe) awakening in a &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt; hospital with little knowledge (amnesia perhaps?) of what had happened, and why he was there, etc. He was told by attending Dr. Jeremy Newman (Stephen Rea) that it was July 29, 2002 (Simon thought it was the year 2000 - he was confused - he heard a doctor say 20:00 hours!) and that he had died for two minutes from cardiac arrest following the near-fatal accident – but he had been revived (“You’re as good as new”).&lt;/span&gt; Dr. Newman: “Simon, this is the 29th of July. The year is 2002. And your wife, whose name is Anna, is waiting outside.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-critiques-say&quot;&gt;What critiques say?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There’s almost no single moment in Portrait of a Lady on Fire that couldn’t be captured, mounted, and hung on a wall as high art.” &lt;cite&gt;— Entertainment Weekly&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major clue to everything that truly happened was the scene that played next under the credits - hospital staff failed to bring a patient back to life with a defibrillator after a car accident. Chest compressions failed and there was no pulse. A second major clue was provided by hospital orderly Travis (Stephen Graham): Everybody dies. No mystery there. But why and how everyone dies. Now, there’s a mystery worth solving. Probably the biggest mystery there is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;so-how-do-we-add-spoilers-in-this-theme&quot;&gt;So how do we add spoilers in this theme?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&amp;gt;My hidden paragraph here.&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://twelvepassed.life/post-with-spoiler/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twelvepassed.life/post-with-spoiler/</guid>
        
        <category>Movies</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>That day when we almost missed our flight</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://twelvepassed.life/that-day-we-almost-missed-flight/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twelvepassed.life/that-day-we-almost-missed-flight/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reviewing the best Oscar movies of all time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Review products, books, movies, restaurant and anything you like on your Jekyll blog with &lt;strong&gt;Memoirs&lt;/strong&gt;! JSON-LD ready for review property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-to-use&quot;&gt;How to use?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s actually really simple! Add the rating in your YAML front matter. It also supports halfs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-md&quot;&gt;---
layout: post
title:  &quot;Inception Movie&quot;
author: john
categories: [ Lifestyle ]
tags: [red, yellow]
image: assets/images/11.jpg
description: &quot;My review of Inception movie. Actors, directing and more.&quot;
rating: 4.5
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://twelvepassed.life/review-oscar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twelvepassed.life/review-oscar/</guid>
        
        <category>Movies</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>French Wine has to compete with many new world wines</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;French wine is produced all throughout France, in quantities between 50 and 60 million hectolitres per year, or 7–8 billion bottles. France is one of the largest wine producers in the world, along with Italian, Spanish, and American wine-producing regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;French wine traces its history to the 6th century BC, with many of France’s regions dating their wine-making history to Roman times. The wines produced range from expensive wines sold internationally to modest wines usually only seen within France such as the Margnat wines were during the post war period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two concepts central to the better French wines are the notion of terroir, which links the style of the wines to the locations where the grapes are grown and the wine is made and the Appellation d’origine contrôlée (AOC) system, replaced by the Appellation d’Origin Protégée (AOP) system in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appellation rules closely define which grape varieties and winemaking practices are approved for classification in each of France’s several hundred geographically defined appellations, which can cover regions, villages or vineyards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;France is the source of many grape varieties (such as &lt;strong&gt;Cabernet Sauvignon, Chardonnay, Pinot noir, Sauvignon blanc, Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;) that are now planted throughout the world, as well as wine-making practices and styles of wine that have been adopted in other producing countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although some producers have benefited in recent years from rising prices and increased demand for some of the prestige wines from Burgundy and Bordeaux, the French wine industry has seen a decline in domestic consumption and internationally, it has had to compete with many new world wines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://twelvepassed.life/french-wine/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twelvepassed.life/french-wine/</guid>
        
        <category>France</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Observer - National Gallery of Art, Washington, United States</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Gallery of Art, and its attached Sculpture Garden, is a national art museum in Washington, D.C., located on the National Mall, between 3rd and 9th Streets, at Constitution Avenue NW. Open to the public and free of charge, the museum was privately established in 1937 for the American people by a joint resolution of the United States Congress. Andrew W. Mellon donated a substantial art collection and funds for construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The core collection includes major works of art donated by Paul Mellon, Ailsa Mellon Bruce, Lessing J. Rosenwald, Samuel Henry Kress, Rush Harrison Kress, Peter Arrell Browne Widener, Joseph E. Widener, and Chester Dale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallery’s collection of paintings, drawings, prints, photographs, sculpture, medals, and decorative arts traces the development of Western Art from the Middle Ages to the present, including the only painting by Leonardo da Vinci in the Americas and the largest mobile created by Alexander Calder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallery’s campus includes the original neoclassical West Building designed by John Russell Pope, which is linked underground to the modern East Building, designed by I. M. Pei, and the 6.1-acre (25,000 m2) Sculpture Garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallery often presents temporary special exhibitions spanning the world and the history of art. It is one of the largest museums in North America.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://twelvepassed.life/the-observer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twelvepassed.life/the-observer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
